Andy Bae Game Designer

I am a versatile game designer specialized in narrative design, systems design, and leadership. Over my 5+ years of experience in game development, I have attained valuable knowledge and skills working on self-published indies, company startup projects, and post-launch updates for top-selling AAA games.

Coquitlam, B.C., Canada

Portfolio:

sjandybae.github.io

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/in/sjandybae

E-mail:

siandybae@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

This Game Studio

Game Designer

October 2022 - October 2023

- Designed 10+ features to improve quality of life and monetization for a top-selling mobile game.
- Wrote all in-game text and NPC dialogue for a massive content update,
 collaborating with creative leads to introduce new lore to the existing IP.
- Led localization processes and improvements to support game development across all departments, including external companies.

"Yet Another Killing Game (YAKG)"

Founder + Director

July 2022 - Present

- Recruited 10+ volunteers to do remote work for a self-started indie game project with <u>a completed demo</u> with 200+ downloads.
- Began managing a 10 month production pipeline for volunteers to maintain consistent monthly deliverables towards the final release date.
- Created mock-ups, flowcharts, and slidedeck presentations to continually present new ideas for the whole team to review.
- Authored 6000+ lines of dialogue and Python code as the lead writer and programmer.

Virtro Entertainment

Game Designer + Narrative Designer

July 2020 - March 2022

- Designed branching storylines and narrative beats for an innovative multilinear VR series pilot backed by the Canada Media Fund.
- Designed branches and wrote all dialogue for a proprietary AI conversation engine used in language learning, job training, and interview simulations.

SKILLS

Unity + C#
Gamemaker Studio 2
Unreal Engine 4 (UE4)
Godot
Python

Design Collaboration
Narrative Design
Systems Design
Gameplay Design
Storytelling
Copywriting
Leadership
Teaching

EDUCATION

Simon Fraser University

B.A. (with Distinction) in Interactive Arts and Technology

June 2020

Surrey, BC

- Completed 16 months of Cooperative Education (Co-op)
- Studied "Narration Across Media" abroad at Malmö University
- Served as Co-founder and Vice President of SFU Manga